Inventory of the Diggs Family Papers 1914-1960
Earl Gregg Swem Library, College of William and Mary
Special Collections, Earl Gregg Swem Library, College of William and Mary
Diggs Family Papers 1914-1960 1920-1940
Special Collections Research Center
01/Mss. Acc. 2007.44
2.50
Business and family papers of the Charles R. and Charles E. Diggs family of Mathews, Virginia and Susan, Virginia. The Diggs Family owed an automobile engine business. In 1921, it was named "Overland and Willys Knight Automobiles Mianus Engines, " but had other names through the years. The family also sold seafood products. Charles Robert Diggs worked in various automotive and machine shops in the area after 1920's.
Diggs, Charles R.; Diggs, Charles Enos arrangement
Administrative Information
Conditions Governing Access
Collection open to all researchers.
Acquisition Information
The materials were acquired by Special Collections Research Center on 00/00/2008.
Biographical Note
Charles R. Diggs lived in Mathews, Virginia. Further information about this individual or organization may be available in the Special Collections Research Center Wiki: http://scrc.swem.wm.edu/wiki/index.php/Charles R. Diggs.
Scope and Contents
Business and family papers of the Charles R. and Charles E. Diggs family of Mathews, Virginia and Susan, Virginia. The Diggs Family owed an automobile engine business. In 1921, it was named "Overland and Willys Knight Automobiles Mianus Engines, " but had other names through the years. The family also sold seafood products. Charles Robert Diggs worked in various automotive and machine shops in the area after 1920's.
Arrangement of Materials
Series 1, Family and Business Documents, is arranged alphabetically by subject, Series 2, Correspondence, is arranged alphabetically by correspondent, then chronologically, Box 2 and 3, Series 3, Financial Records, is arranged alphabetically by type of record.
Additional Information
Index Terms
This Collection is indexed under the following controlled access subject terms.
Genre/Form of Material:
Correspondence; Photographs; Receipts (financial records)
Topical Term:
Account books.; Ledgers (Accounting)
Detailed Description of the Collection
- Family and Business Documents, 1899-1971; id27140
  - id27136 (Box 1)
    - Bank Documents, 1920, 1971and undated; id27060 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Bills – Telephone, 1942-1943; id27061 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Brochures and Calendars, 1929 and undated; id27062 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Cards – License, Business, Insurance, undated; id27063 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Diggs, Charles R., 1947 and undated; id27064 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Diggs, Lillian P. (Mrs. Charles R.), 1927-49; id27065 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Documents – Business, 1920-1941 and undated; id27066 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Documents – Business, 1923, 1932 and undated; id27067 (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - Documents – Business and Personal, 1913-1943 and undated.; id27069 (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - Envelopes, Empty, 1924, 1953-55; id27068 (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - Genealogy, id27070 (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - Loan – Charles Aubey, undated; id27071 (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - Medical, Undated; id27072 (Box 1, Folder 13)
    - Newspaper Clippings, Undated; id27073 (Box 1, Folder 14)
    - Papers, Undated.; id27120 (Box 1, Folder 15)
    - Photograph - Five Generations of Women, Undated; id27121 (Box 1, Folder 16)
    - Photographs - Negatives, Undated; id27122 (Box 1, Folder 17)
    - Real Estate, 1911, 1915, 1919, 1929, 1936; id27074 (Box 1, Folder 18)
    - Real Estate – Deeds, 1899, 1927 and undated.; id27075 (Box 1, Folder 19)
    - Receipts – Business and Personal, 1904-1942; id27076 (Box 1, Folder 20)
    - Recipe – Kickapoo Joy Juice, Undated; id27077 (Box 1, Folder 21)
    - School Items, 1919, 1922, 1923 and undated; id27078 (Box 1, Folder 22)
    - Taxes, 1940, 1955, 1965, 1968; id27079 (Box 1, Folder 23)
    - Tilton, Dexter, 1898, 1933 and undated; id27080 (Box 1, Folder 24)
- Family and Business Correspondence, 1913-1963; id27141
  - id27143 (Box 1)
    - Cards for Special Occasions, Undated; id27082 (Box 1, Folder 24)
    - Mr. Charles R. Diggs, 1913; id27083 (Box 1, Folder 25)
    - Mr. Charles R. Diggs, 1920; id27084 (Box 1, Folder 26)
    - Mr. Charles R. Diggs, 1921; id27091 (Box 1, Folder 27)
    - Mr. Charles R. Diggs, January - June 1922; id27092 (Box 1, Folder 28)
    - Mr. Charles R. Diggs, August 1922; id27093 (Box 1, Folder 29)
    - Mr. Charles R. Diggs, September 1922; id27094 (Box 1, Folder 30)
    - Mr. Charles R. Diggs, October - November 1922; id27095 (Box 1, Folder 31)
    - Mr. Charles R. Diggs, December 1922; id27096 (Box 1, Folder 32)
    - Mr. Charles R. Diggs, January 1923; id27097 (Box 1, Folder 33)
    - Mr. Charles R. Diggs, February - March, 1923; id27098 (Box 1, Folder 34)
    - Mr. Charles R. Diggs, April - June 1923; id27099 (Box 1, Folder 35)
    - Mr. Charles R. Diggs, July-October 1923; id27100 (Box 1, Folder 36)
    - Mr. Charles R. Diggs, April - May 1924; id27101 (Box 1, Folder 37)
    - Mr. Charles R. Diggs, June 1924; id27102 (Box 1, Folder 38)
    - Mr. Charles R. Diggs, July-December 1924; id27103 (Box 1, Folder 39)
    - Mr. Charles R. Diggs, 1924; id27104 (Box 1, Folder 40)
    - Mr. Charles R. Diggs, 1925-1928; id27105 (Box 1, Folder 41)
    - Mr. Charles R. Diggs, 1932-1935; id27106 (Box 1, Folder 42)
    - Mr. Charles R. Diggs, January - September 1936; id27107 (Box 1, Folder 43)
    - Mrs. Charles R. Diggs, May-June 1937; id27108 (Box 1, Folder 44)
    - Mr. Charles R. Diggs, August 1937; id27109 (Box 1, Folder 45)
    - Mr. Charles R. Diggs, 1938-1963; id27110 (Box 1, Folder 46)
    - Mr. Charles R. Diggs, Undated.; id27111 (Box 1, Folder 47)
    - Mr. Charles E. Diggs, 1922; id27112 (Box 1, Folder 48)
    - Mr. Charles E. Diggs, 1923; id27113 (Box 1, Folder 49)
    - Mr. Charles E. Diggs, 1924; id27114 (Box 1, Folder 50)
    - Mr. Charles E. Diggs, 1925; id27115 (Box 1, Folder 51)
    - Mrs. Charles E. Diggs (Linda Diggs), 1922-1925; id27116 (Box 1, Folder 52)
    - Mrs. Charles E. Diggs (Linda Diggs), 1924 - 1940; id27117 (Box 1, Folder 53)
    - Correspondence – Personal, 1922-24; id27118 (Box 1, Folder 54)
    - Correspondence - Warner Moss, 1962-63; id27119 (Box 1, Folder 55)
- Financial Records, 1914-1950; id27123
  - id27124 (Box 2)
    - Check Registers, 1921-1941; id27125 (Box 2, Folder 1)
    - Invoices, 1939-1941; id27126 (Box 2, Folder 2)
    - Ledger, 1928-1931; id27127 (Box 2, Folder 3)
    - Ledger, 1936-1940; id27128 (Box 2, Folder 4)
    - Ledger, 1941-1966; id27129 (Box 2, Folder 5)
    - Ledger and Day Book, 1927-1928, 1945; id27130 (Box 2, Folder 6)
    - Ledger for Citizens Cooperation League of Chesapeake District, 1914-1917; id27131 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - id27132 (Box 3)
    - Bank Deposit Books, 1931-1939; id27133 (Box 3, Folder 1)
    - Bank Deposit Books, 1931-1939; id27134 (Box 3, Folder 2)
    - Receipt Books, 1916:1950; id27135 (Box 3, Folder 3)